<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>My personal blog</title><link href="http://andreacrotti.github.com/personal-blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://andreacrotti.github.com/personal-blog//feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://andreacrotti.github.com/personal-blog/</id><updated>2012-03-18T13:49:23+00:00</updated><entry><title>Thoughts from PyCon US</title><link href="http://andreacrotti.github.com/personal-blog//thoughts-from-pycon-us.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-18T13:49:23+00:00</updated><author><name>Andrea Crotti</name></author><id>http://andreacrotti.github.com/personal-blog//thoughts-from-pycon-us.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- roads --&gt;
&lt;!-- links --&gt;
&lt;!-- robots --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an amazing week I'm sadly going back to the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two PyCon Italy and one Europycon last year this time I decided that I really wanted to come to Pycon Us, and I'm very glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="trip"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from Bristol has been an exhausting trip, with the 3-4 hours
delay of the airplane in London in took me exactly 24 hours from the
time I left my house to the time I got to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had only some vague ideas about what the silicon valley really is,
but the first and most impressive thing is definitively the sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is bigger there, roads, buildings and cars, Santa Clara
seems to be designed for giants or for cars, definitively not for
human beings without wheels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorials"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Thursday I did my first and only tutorial, still slightly KO from
the jet-lag and the long trip.  It started well but it became quite
boring in the end, and there wasn't any hands-on session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly I don't see the point of a tutorial composed &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; of slides
and demos which I can't even possibly reproduce.  I understand that
it's hard to set up and to get something useful done it's not easy,
but it's really not fulfilling to watch someone else doing a demo
without even understanding what he's doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One possible solution would be to prepare all the boiler-plate code
before, and make it available (even before the tutorial) to the people
attending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a clear set of prepared tools and modules that abstracts the
boring parts it would much easier to actually get something nice done
during the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conference"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday it was the great day, and we started off with an amazing
robot-dance, it was absolutely awesome, these little robots really
look humans, and I can only imagine how hard it must be to program
a synchronized choreograph with such natural movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprints"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sprints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first sprint session and I'm very glad I did it.  After
Sunday night I thought that only a few people would have actually
remained, I was quite wrong and on Monday apparently more than 700
people were still in the hotel coding like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first joined the python-dev group and thanks to Martin Löwis I now
have a very work flow to contribute, with my own clone of the CPython
sources on bitbucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I joined Barry Warsaw and the GNU Mailman team, and after one day
I already had a couple of branches merged into trunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- special thanks to the foundation --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>